Guide to the English Documents Collection, 1552-1875
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
English Documents Collection
1552-1875
Vassar College. Library
15 cubic feet (325 items in 15 boxes and 6 mapcase drawers)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Deeds, leases, apprenticeship indentures rent rolls, wills, customs certificates and other legal documents, mostly from Devon, Kent and Somerset.
Scope and Content Note
Deeds, leases, apprenticeship indentures rent rolls, wills, customs certificates and other legal documents, mostly from Devon, Kent and Somerset.
A list created in 1979 mentions a "1551 court roll, Shrubwell, Buttscombe & L, Somerset," but it has either been mislabeled or mislaid as of March 2014.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Real property--England--Devon; Real property--England--Kent; Real property--England--Somerset; Probate Records--England--Devon; Probate Records--England--Kent; Probate Records--England--Somerset
Places:
Devon (England)--Genealogy--Sources; Devon (England)--History--Sources; Kent (England)--Genealogy--Sources; Kent (England)--History--Sources; Somerset (England)--Genealogy--Sources; Somerset (England)--History--Sources
VCL Categories
Medieval and Early Modern Manuscripts
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007.
Updated by Laura Streett/Streett, February 2008 and March 2014.
Acquisition Information
According to a collection inventory (completed presumably by Nat Alcock in 1979), the material was "apparently bought in London in 1938, and presented to the College thereafter, by a faculty member." However, according to a 1967 list of manuscript collections at Vassar, compiled by librarian Frances Goudy, the collection was a gift of Dorothy Meigs Eidlitz, Vassar Class of 1914.
Arrangement
This collection is intellectually arranged in seven series, and chronologically within each of those series. It is physically arranged according to the size of the document.
Series List
- Series I. Deeds
- Series II. Wills
- Series III. Apprenticeship Indentures
- Series IV. Marriage Settlements
- Series V. Church Records
- Series VI. Customs Bonds and Certificates
- Series VII. Miscellaneous
Container List
- SERIES I. DEEDS
  - Devon
    - Aveton Gifford, Devon, 10 July 1637; (14" x 21.5") (Folder 8.03)
    - Cleyhanger, Devon, 20 October 1680; (13" x 9.5") (Folder 4.08)
    - Brandninch, Devon, 13 June 1687; (15" x 15.5") (Folder 4.10)
    - Diptford, Devon, 16 July 1692; (25" x 26.5") (Folder M.29)
    - Diptford, Devon, 16 July 1692; (26" x 27.5") (Folder M.30)
    - Diptford, Devon, 16 July 1692; (24" x 28") (Folder M.31)
    - Diptford, Devon, 16 July 1692; (27" x 29") (Folder M.32)
    - Exeter, Devon, 1 May 1714; (11" x 16") (Folder 4.22)
    - Exeter, Devon, 30 April 1714; (10.5" x 15") (Folder 11.07)
    - South Leigh; Honiton, Devon, 1 July 1736; (26.5" x 32") (Folder M.42)
    - Barnstaple Quay, copy of property description, 6 October 1737; (7.5" x 9") (Folder 1.32)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 16 October 1737; (13.5" x 22") (Folder 13.02)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 15 September 1745; (27.5" x 35") (Folder M.43)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 23 February 1748; (18.5" x 25") (Folder 13.10)
    - Paignton, Devon, 12 December 1747; (26.5" x 35") (Folder M.44)
    - Lifton, Devon, 24 March 1748 or 1749; (17" x 27") (Folder 13.12)
    - Harberton, Devon, 22 July 1752; (13" x 16.5") (Folder 5.15)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 5 December 1754; (23.5" x 29.5") (Folder M.20)
    - Axmouth, etc., Devon, 1762; (14" x 18") (Folder 5.19)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 13 June 1767; (19" x 25.5") (Folder 14.05)
    - Ilfracombe, Devon, 29 September 1770; (28" x 34") (Folder M.47)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 14 November 1792; (32.5" x 36") (Folder M.51)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 30 January 1794; (27" x 32.5") (Folder M.53)
    - Barnstaple, Devon, 30 July 1830; (25" x 29.5") (Folder M.54)
  - KENT
    - Chatham, Kent, 10 January 1615; (12" x 25") (Folder 7.05)
    - Lydd, Kent, 16 June1660; (12.5" x 15.5") (Folder 4.04)
    - Hever, Chepsted, Kingsdown & Mapplecombe, Kent, 23 February 1664; (21" x 30.5") (Folder M.04)
    - Southwell Manor, Biddinden, Kent, 15 August 1682; (11.5" x 16") (Folder 4.09)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 29-30 August 1687; (12.5" x 22") (Folder 10.05)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 30 August 1687; (22" x 28") (Folder M.08)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 14 April 1687; (18" x 23") (Folder 10.04)
    - Ockley, Kent, 25 September 1699; (14" x 17") (Folder 4.16)
    - Tonbridge, Som. Haldlow, Leigh, Tuedley, Penbury, Kent. includes a platt of the pieces concerned, 28 November 1702; (24.5" x 32.5") (Folder M.33)
    - Tonbridge, Kent, 2 February 1707; (23.5" x 32") (Folder M.10)
    - Tonbridge, Kent, 11 November 1709; (26" x 32") (Folder M.34)
    - Dartford, Kent, 1 December 1709; (12.5" x 16") (Folder 4.20)
    - Tunbridge Wells, 24 February 1712; (24.5" x 27.5") (Folder M.35)
    - Tunbridge, Kent, 20 April 1713; (12.5" x 23.5") (Folder 11.05)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 24 May 1716; (18" x 26.5") (Folder 11.08)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 25 May 1716; (30.5" x 34") (Folder M.36)
    - Tunbridge, Kent, 17 July 1716; (12" x 23.5") (Folder 11.09)
    - Speldhurst Common; Bishops Down, Kent, 20 April 1719; (12.5" x 16") (Folder 5.01)
    - Tunbridge Wells, K; the Great House – attached long inventory of house contents, 10 March 1719 or 1720; (21.5" x 28.5") (Folder M.13)
    - Tunbridge, Wells, Kent, 24 June 1721; (25.5" x 29") (Folder M.38)
    - Tunbridge, Wells, Kent, 24 June 1721; (24.5" x 31.5") (Folder M.39)
    - Whitstable, Kent, 1 May 1723; (18" x 29.5") (Folder M.15)
    - Swadlands; Speldhurst, Kent, 1 November 1725; (20.5" x 25") (Folder 12.04)
    - Speldhurst & Tunbridge, Kent, 1-2 October 1728; (16.5" x 26") (Folder 12.03)
    - Speldhurst & Tunbridge, Kent, 2 October 1728; (25.5" x 34") (Folder M.40)
    - Tunbridge, Kent, slip abstracting deed, 23 December 1734; (5" x 8") (Folder 1.26)
    - Tunbridge, Kent, 23 December 1734; (17.5" x 24.5") (Folder 12.10)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 19 June 1739; (13" x 20.5") (Folder M.18)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 20 June 1739; (20.5" x 26.5") (Folder 13.04)
    - Tunbridge Wells, Kent, 20 June 1739; (20" x 25") (Folder 13.05)
    - Tonbridge, Kent, 27 October 1743; (22.5" x 26") (Folder M.19)
    - Speldhurst, Kent, 4 November 1747; (10.5" x 15") (Folder 5.12)
    - Speldhurst, Kent, 4-5 November 1747; (18.5" x 21") (Folder 13.09)
    - Lyminge, Kent, 27 November 1750; (13.5" x 21.5") (Folder 14.01)
    - Plumstead, Kent, 15 March 1753; (13.5" x 21") (Folder 14.02)
    - Speldhurst, Kent, 25 October 1768; (27.5" x 35") (Folder M.46)
    - Speldhurst, Kent, 4 January 1774; (15" x 19") (Folder 5.21)
    - Canterbury, Kent, 23 January 1787; (13" x 16.5") (Folder 6.04)
    - Chelsfield, Kent, 24 May 1792; (16" x 21.5") (Folder 14.08)
    - Chelsfield, Kent, 25 May 1792; (27" x 32.5") (Folder M.52)
  - Somerset
    - Blagdon Manor, Som, 2 April 1612; (23" x 27") (Folder M.01)
    - Lullington Mill, Som, 24 May 1611; (17.5" x 25") (Folder 7.03)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 25 March 1613; (9.5" x 22.5") (Folder 7.04)
    - Templecombe, Som, 22 June 1621; (26" x 31") (Folder M.23)
    - Blagdon, Som, 6 August 1630; (16.5" x 21") (Folder 7.07)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 3 March 1631; (17.5" x 21.5") (Folder 8.01)
    - Templecombe, Som, 17 November 1632; (23" x 27.5") (Folder M.02)
    - Templecombe, Som, 20 October 1632; (27" x 31.5") (Folder M.24)
    - Barrow Minchin, Som, 13 February 1634; (20" x 24") (Folder 8.02)
    - Blagdon, Som, 24 April 1649; (14" x 25.5") (Folder 8.04)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 20 March 1651 or 1652; (11" x 25" - 2 copies) (Folder 8.05)
    - Templecombe, Som, 13 February 1651; (22.5" x 30") (Folder M.03)
    - Henstridge, Som, 12 February 1658; (12.5" x 26.5") (Folder 8.06)
    - Blagdon, Som, 9 May 1661; (25" x 32") (Folder M.25)
    - Banwell, Som, 18 March 1662; (12.5" x 14") (Folder 4.05)
    - Sparlgrove & Westcombe, Som, 24 August 1665; (9.5" x 20") (Folder 8.08)
    - Templecome, Som & Westhope, Camb/Hunts., 25 April 1664; (17" x 22.5") (Folder 8.07)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 6 May 1669; (10.5" x 31") (Folder M.05)
    - Baltonsborough, exch. of open field land in Northfield there., 20 December 1671; (10" x 16.5") (Folder 4.07)
    - South Barrow, Som, 26 April 1671; (13" x 25.5") (Folder 9.01)
    - Woolton, Buckleigh, Som & Baltonsborough, Som, 12 April 1672; (26" x 29") (Folder M.26)
    - Batcombe, Som, 29 March 1673; (14" x 25") (Folder 9.04)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 19 March 1672; (19.5" x 26.5") (Folder 9.03)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 30 December 1675; (15.5" x 29") (Folder M.06)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 10 May 1671; (12.5" x 26") (Folder 9.02)
    - South Barrow, Som, 26 July 1676; (6.5" x 25.5") (Folder 9.05)
    - South Barrow, Som, 26 July 1676; (12" x 26") (Folder 9.06)
    - Templecombe Manor, Som, 26 October 1676 (Folder M.07)
    - Westcombe, Batcombe, Som, 3 March 1681; (5" x 25") (Folder 9.07)
    - Hungerford Farley, Som, 23 September 1681; (25" x 27.5") (Folder M.27)
    - Templecombe, Som, 23 August 1682; (17" x 25") (Folder 9.08)
    - Barhayes Manor, Som; long schedule of property reserved, 25 June 1684; (11" x 23") (Folder 10.01)
    - Barhayes Manor, Som; long schedule of property reserved, 25 June 1684; (28" x 35") (Folder M.28)
    - Westcombe, Batcombe, Som, 21 April 1684; (7.5" x 21.5") (Folder 9.10)
    - Westcombe, Batcombe, Som, 22 April 1684; (15" x 24.5") (Folder 9.09)
    - Westcombe, Som, 22 May 1685; (11.5" x 23") (Folder 10.02)
    - Abbots Leigh, Som, 20 September 1686; (17" x 20.5") (Folder 10.03)
    - House sometime burntdown now re-edified, known as House on the Heath, Bedminster, Som, 3 September 1687; (16" x 24") (Folder 10.06)
    - Bathampton, Som, 20 October 1693; (13" x 19") (Folder 4.14)
    - Barrow Gurney, Somerset, signed by Sarah and William Hasell of Bristol, 9 September 1693; (14" x 18") (Folder 4.12)
    - Butmore, Baltonsboroough, Som, 23 November 1695; (23" x 24") (Folder M.09)
    - Abbot Leigh, Som; that Great House lately built, 22 June1695; (16.5" x 23.5") (Folder 10.07)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 15 November 1699; (9" x 21") (Folder 10.08)
    - Batcombe, Som, 8 May 1700; (17.5" x 20") (Folder 10.09)
    - Beckington, Som, 13 February 1701 or 1702; (14" x 21.5") (Folder 10.11)
    - Beckington, Som, 15 April 1701; (10" x 23") (Folder 10.10)
    - Beckington Som, 16 February 1701 or 1702; (20" x 24.5") (Folder 11.01)
    - Tonbridge, Som. Haldlow, Leigh, Tuedley, Penbury, Kent. includes a platt of the pieces concerned, 28 November 1702; (24.5" x 32.5") (Folder M.33)
    - Batheaston, Som, 20 October 1703; (14" x 22") (Folder 11.02)
    - Banwell, Som, 3 May 1706; (12" x 14.5") (Folder 4.19)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 25 November 1705; (10" x 20") (Folder 4.18)
    - Abbotscombe, Som, 9 March 1709; (11.5" x 21.5") (Folder 11.03)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 23 February 1709; (22" x 29") (Folder M.11)
    - Long Ashton, Som, 3 December 1712; (18.5" x 23") (Folder 11.04)
    - Ashbrittle, Som, 5 April 1714; (13.5" x 21.5") (Folder 11.06)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 10 January 1716; (11" x 17") (Folder 4.23)
    - Beckington, Som, 11 June 1718; (14" x 17.5") (Folder 4.24)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 3 December 1718; (18" x 27") (Folder 12.01)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 31 December 1718; (24.5" x 28") (Folder M.37)
    - North St., Bedminster, Som, 24 January 1718 or 1719; (23" x 27") (Folder M.12)
    - Abbotscombe, Somerset, 24 September 1719; (11.5" x 19") (Folder 11.11)
    - Beckington, Som, 1 June 1721; (20" x 30") (Folder M.14)
    - Blagdon, Som, 17 February 1726; (16" x 20") (Folder 12.05)
    - Blagdon, Som, 3 April 1728; (16.5" x 23.5") (Folder 12.06)
    - Blagdon, Som, 2 June 1731; (26" x 32") (Folder M.41)
    - Templecombe, Som, 1 August 1731; (16.5" x 10") (Folder 5.06)
    - Templecombe, Som, 1-2 August 1731; (30" x 32") (Folder M.16)
    - Blagdon, Som, 16 August 1731; (17" x 24.5") (Folder 12.09)
    - Blagdon, Som, 1 February 1736; (17.5" x 21") (Folder 13.01)
    - Bedminster, Som, 11 February 1736 or 1737; (24" x 30") (Folder M.17)
    - Blagdon, Som, 29 June 1738; (23" x 27") (Folder 13.03)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 30 September 1741; (13" x 20.5") (Folder 13.06)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 12 October 1744; (10" x 19.5") (Folder 5.10)
    - Baltonsborough, Som, 13 October 1744; (17" x 27.5") (Folder 13.07)
    - Ashweek, Som, 26 December 1744; (13.5" x 20") (Folder 13.08)
    - Bedminster, Som, 23 September 1748; (18" x 24.5") (Folder 13.11)
    - Long Ashton, Som, 19 March 1755; (21.5" x 27.5") (Folder 14.03)
    - Blagdon, Som, 24 February 1759; (17.5" x 24") (Folder 14.04)
    - Ashweek, Som, 16 September 1762; (25" x 32") (Folder M.45)
    - Ashweek, Som, 25 July 1781; (12.5" x 20.5") (Folder 14.06)
    - Blagdon, Som, 12 April 1782; (12" x 19.5") (Folder 5.24)
    - Batcombe, Som; printed leases by Duke of Chandos, 24 June 1785; (26.5" x 30") (Folder M.48)
    - Batcombe, Som; printed leases by Duke of Chandos, 24 June 1785; (27" x 30") (Folder M.49)
    - Batcombe, Som; printed leases by Duke of Chandos, 24 June 1785; (27" x 30") (Folder M.50)
    - Blagdon, Som, 21 February 1792; (14" x 17.5") (Folder 6.05)
    - South Barrow, Som; rectory, 15 September 1801; (20" x 29.5") (Folder M.21)
- SERIES II. WILLS
  - Devon
    - Will of Margaret [Kech?], Bigbury, Devon., 13 December 1702; (7.5" x 12") (Folder 1.12)
    - Will of James Ayres, Honiton, Devon, 6 January 1705; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 1.14)
    - Will of Francis Stout, Holbeton, Devon, 23 August 1711; (9.5" x 14.5") (Folder 4.21)
    - Will of Robert Bennett, Halmston, Devon, 2 June 1741; (10" x 15.5") (Folder 5.09)
    - Will of John Wood, Farway, Devon, 7 May 1746; (9.5" x 15.5") (Folder 5.13)
    - Will of John Penneck, Barley, Devon, 1 March 1750; (9.5" x 15") (Folder 5.14)
    - Release signed by Gertrude Chope, Bideford regarding the will of Roger Wollocombe of Roborough, Devon, 28 November 1755; (15" x 19.5") (Folder 5.17)
    - Will of William Palmer, Devon, 10 February 1783; (12.5" x 15.5") (Folder 14.07)
    - Will codicil of John Walker Foote, Beer Ferris, Devon, 9 October 1810; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.13)
    - Will and codicil of Benjamin Mardon, Exeter, Devon, 12 July 1813; (13" x 16") (Folder 6.13)
    - Residuary Account — Stamps and Taxes Form for the estate of Mary Froude, Denbury Devon, 28 October 1839; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.37)
  - Kent
    - Will and probate of Anne Pembroke, Boughton under the Blean, Kent, 5 April 1726; (11" x 14.5") (Folder 5.02)
    - Legacy receipts and Will of Hannah Gilpin, Sevenoaks, Kent, 28 April 1727; (12" x 15.5") (Folder 5.04)
    - Will of Elizabeth Hills, Dartford, Kent, 26 December 1729; (12.5" x 15.5") (Folder 5.05)
    - Discharges, re will Thomas Ballard, High Halden, Kent, August 1791; (5 pages) (Folder 1.41)
    - Will of Elizabeth Whitaker, Pembury, Kent, August 1806; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.11)
    - Will of John Walker Foote, March [Devon or Kent?], 9 October 1810; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.13)
    - Will of John Smith, Herne Bay, Kent, 7 September 1835; (24.5" x 28.5") (Folder M.55)
  - Somerset
    - Will of William (Th?)(Fl)etcher of Butcombe, Som., 26 April 1652; (14" x 18.5") (Folder 4.02)
    - Will of Symon Brimstead, Hilbishop, Som., 20 September 1654; (11.5" x 14.5") (Folder 4.03)
    - Will of James Davison of Westcombe, Batcombe, Som, 12 July 1693; (12.5" x 15") (Folder 4.13)
    - Will of Henry Davison, Westcombe, Batcombe, Som, 4 January 1705; (12.5" x 18") (Folder 4.17)
    - Will of William Carter, Beckington, Som, 20 or 23 July 1717; (18" x 23.5") (Folder 11.10)
    - Will of John Stone, Ashbrittle, Som, 7 October 1718; (16.5" x 19") (Folder 11.12)
    - Will of Richard Welch [Somerset?], 13 June 1721; (12" x 15.5") (Folder 5.03)
    - Probate Grant of Richard Welch [Somerset?], 13 June 1721; (12" x 15.5") (Folder 5.03)
    - Will & copy, Thomas Davison of Westcombe, Som, 6 March 1722; (7.5" x 12") (Folder 1.18)
    - Will & copy, Thomas Davison of Westcombe, Som, 6 March 1722; (19.5" x 27") (Folder 12.02)
    - Will of James Tree, Som, 8 December 1729; (12.5" x 22.5") (Folder 12.07)
    - Will of Samuel Palmer, Som, 6 October 1730; (18" x 23.5") (Folder 12.08)
    - Copy of 1757 will of Philip Tabor of Burrow Lane, Somerset, used in probate of his wife, 31 May 1759; (6.5" x 15") (Folder 5.18)
    - Will of Elizabeth Dabine, Pedweek, Ashcott, Som, 30 June 1780; (10" x 13") (Folder 5.23)
    - Will of Sarah Batterbury, Bath, Som, 18 December 1785; (10" x 16") (Folder 6.01)
    - Will of Edward Chapman, Som, 30 May 1833; (12" x 20.5") (Folder 14.15)
    - Will of Thomas Bessem, Beominster, Som, 18 August 1836; (14.5" x 16") (Folder 6.17)
    - Will of John Bird, Ashbrittle, Som. — copy of 1718/1719 or 1818/1819 original, n.d.; (13.5" x 16.5") (Folder 7.01)
  - Unidentified and Miscellaneous
    - Will of William Babb, Gurlyn, Cornwall, 19 July 1791; (7.5" x 12.5") (Folder 1.40)
    - Will of Jonas Blandford, Stapleton, Glouster, 2 November 1801 or 1804; (16.5" x 20.5") (Folder 14.09)
    - Will of Samuel Kentish (Lt. Royal Navy), 11 February 1827; (16.5" x 20") (Folder 14.12)
    - Will of Francis Lee, London, 14 December 1838; (15.5" x 17.5") (Folder 6.18)
- SERIES III. APPRENTICESHIP INDENTURES
  - Devon
    - Apprenticeship Indenture, Husbandry, Devon, 22 April 1796; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.06)
    - Apprenticeship Indenture of Henry May as a shoemaker, Devon, 15 March 1859; (10" x 14") (Folder 6.23)
  - Kent
    - Apprenticeship Indenture as apothecary to Thomas Crutteden of Cranbrooke, Kent, 1 March 1692; (12" x 15.5") (Folder 4.11)
    - Apprenticeship Indenture, Kent, 25 May 1797; (13.5" x 16") (Folder 6.08)
    - Apprenticeship Indenture of Peter Brown as a barber, Kent, 6 December 1828; (10" x 14") (Folder 6.16)
    - Apprenticeship Indenture, Butchery, Kent, 13 March 1845; (9" x 10") (Folder 2.39)
    - Apprenticeship Indenture of Thomas Stevens as a sailmaker, Bideford, Kent, 18 September 1865; (9.5" x 14") (Folder 6.24)
- SERIES IV. MARRIAGE SETTLEMENTS
  - Devon
    - Letter regarding marriage settlement between Anne and Ralph Barnes, archdeacon of Totnes, Devon, contested after the death of Ralph Barnes, 6 September 1820; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 2.22)
    - Proposal by Earl of Morley regarding the marriage settlement of Mr & Mrs Stapleton – refers to Hardwick estate & Cholwich, Cornwood, Devon, 1839; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 2.35)
  - Kent
    - Inventory attached to marriage settlement betweeen Ann Brookhouse and Thomas Dolby, Canterbury, Kent, 14 February 1809; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.12)
  - Somerset
    - Settlement regarding the marriage of John [Knotting?] the Younger and Marie Saffyn, Bicknoller and Stogumber, Somerset, 10 September 1610; (16" x 25.5") (Folder 7.06)
- SERIES V. CHURCH RECORDS
  - Devon
    - Certificate of Declaration of Adherence to the Act of Uniformity and the Act Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy by John Ross when he became the Bishop of Exeter, Canterbury, Devon, 23 January 1778; (7.5" x 12.5") (Folder 1.37)
    - Sacrament Certificate Totnes, Devon: Parish Register, 1805 - 1827; (20 certificates, 7" x 9.5") (Folders 3.01 - 3.20)
  - Kent
    - Baptismal record of Thomas, late son of John Sheafe, Bethersden, Kent, 24 May 1686; (3.5" x 6") (Folder 2.43)
    - Extract from the Register of St. Pauls, Deptford Kent recording the marriage of Benjamin Cole of All Hallows, Lombard Street, [London], and Frances Wager, spinster, of St Pauls, Deptford on 23 Dec 1746, (5" x 8") (Folder 2.44)
    - Baptism Certificate of William and Thomas Oben, East Malling, Kent, 27 August 1792; (6" x 12") (Folder 2.02)
  - Somerset
    - Permission granted by John, Bishop of Bath and Wells, to remove (at the request of Mary Davison) certain pews of the church at Batcombe, Somerset, 20 October 1741; (12" x 19") (Folder 5.08)
- SERIES VI. CUSTOMS BONDS AND CERTIFICATES
  - Customs Bond from Reign of Charles II, 1680; (4.5" x 8") (Folder 1.05)
  - Customs Bond and Certificate, 1694; (4.5" x 8") (Folder 1.08)
  - Customs Bond and Certificate, 7 March 1695; (4.5" x 8") (Folder 1.09)
  - Customs Certificate w/ Gov. Stamp, 4 April 1695; (4.5" x 8") (Folder 1.10)
  - Customs Certificate w/ Gov. Stamp, 26 June 1704; (5" x 6.5") (Folder 1.13)
  - Landing Certificate, Dartmouth, 4 April 1734; (7" x 12") (Folder 1.24)
  - Landing Certificate, Plymouth, 4 May 1743; (5" x 9.5") (Folder 1.28)
  - Customs Certificate w/ Gov. Stamp, 3 May 1745; (5" x 7") (Folder 1.29)
  - Customs Certificate w/ Gov. Stamp, 16 July 1782; (6" x 8") (Folder 1.38)
  - License and customs agreement signed by Thomas Wills and Robert Black regarding the export of wool to London from Barnstaple, Devon, 6 September 1792; (10" x 16") (Folder 6.06)
  - Landing Certificate, Port Barnstaple, 21 September 1792; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 2.03)
  - Landing Certificate, Bristol, 19 October 1792; (6.5" x 8") (Folder 2.04)
  - Customs Certificate, 10 April 1813; (8" x 9.5") (Folder 2.14)
  - Landing Certificate, Port Whitehaven, 3 August 1816; (8" x 8") (Folder 2.15)
- SERIES VII. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Devon
    - Request for Ann Bussel to appear in court as a witness in the trial of Edward [Hurfe?] for "felonious stealing of half a crowne from her," Cadleigh, Devon, ca. 1660-1685; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.02)
    - Agreement to sell, Philip Hooper from Anthony Eveleigh, Farrington, Devon [now Sowton], 1 April 1710; (7.5" x 12") (Folder 1.15)
    - Agreement between John Smith of Shobrooke, Devon, and his creditors, 9 April 1730; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 1.23)
    - Accounts received for Arthur Farwell in Ashburton and Totnes, Devon, 1733-1736; (13" x 16.5") (Folder 5.07)
    - 1734 copy 12 January 1733 document regarding the bankrupcy and creditors of John Anstey of Tiverton, Devon, 15 October 1734; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 1.25)
    - Fine – Milton Abbot & Ermington, Stephen Maddaford, pl.; John& Mary Prout, John & Sarah Hawkins – 2 Mess, 3 gdns, 20 ac. Land, 4 ac. Mead., 2 ac. Pasture, Devon, 1745; (9" x 18") (Folder 5.11)
    - Receipt for annuity payable from Fishley Devon, 23 April 1751; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 1.30)
    - File of lawyers a/cs – Mr Henry Beavis to P.M. Docton. Esq., Barnstaple, Devon, 1754, 1758; (5 documents) (Folder 1.31)
    - Document regarding debt owed to William Parry and William Makean by Joseph Guest, Cullompton, Devon, 1773; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 1.35)
    - Document from Chancery Court case, March1773; (10.5" x 15.5") (Folder 5.20)
    - Petition by John Merivale to receive the remains of his parents estate from Jonathan Green, Tavistock, Devon, 21 May 1774; (12.5" x 7.5") (Folder 1.36)
    - Schedule of deeds belonging to Miss Harris of Pickwell, Devon, re Cornish lands, incl, tin & copper setts. 1750 on, 28 July 1778; (15" x 19") (Folder 5.22)
    - Document regarding a complaint by Peter Goodright against Stephen Badtitle regarding farming rights, Devon, June 1786; (10" x 10.5") (Folder 6.02)
    - Bill of Complaint by Chancellor Baron Edward Thurlow, Ashfield, Suffolk, regarding the estate of Addis Archer and his heirs, Plymouth, Devon, 26 July 1786; (10.5" x 15") (Folder 6.03)
    - Copy, fine re manor of Torre, Devon, Baron Cliffor of Chudleigh and Charles Butler, Esq., plaintiffs, 1795; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 2.05)
    - Calculation of value of manors of Maristow, Buckland, Monachorum, Bickleigh, Shaugh Prior, Walkhampton, Devon from printed particulars of rents, ca. 1800; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 2.07)
    - Letter from the new Bishop of Exeter to Mr. [Francis] Freeling about his franking priviledge, 26 June [180?]; (7.5" x 9") (Folder 2.46)